[
    {
        "question": "In Angular, you can pass data from parent component to child component using...",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "@Output()"
            },
            {
                "B": "@Input()"
            },
            {
                "C": "Input"
            },
            {
                "D": "Output"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In Angular, you can pass data from child component to parent component using",
        "answer": "A",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "@Output()"
            },
            {
                "B": "@Input()"
            },
            {
                "C": "Input"
            },
            {
                "D": "Output"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "You can create local HTML reference of HTML tag using variable which starts with character?",
        "answer": "1",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "@"
            },
            {
                "B": "#"
            },
            {
                "C": "*"
            },
            {
                "D": "&"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "A directive which modifies DOM hierarchy is called?",
        "answer": "A",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "Structural directive"
            },
            {
                "B": "Attribute directive"
            },
            {
                "C": null
            },
            {
                "D": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Select correct form control class name which is set to true via [(ngModel)] whenever value is modified?",
        "answer": "D",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "ng-invalid"
            },
            {
                "B": "ng-pending"
            },
            {
                "C": "ng-pristine"
            },
            {
                "D": "ng-dirty"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "If you provide a custom service in two components’ “providers” section of @Component decorator, how many instances of service shall get created?",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "1"
            },
            {
                "B": "2"
            },
            {
                "C": "3"
            },
            {
                "D": "4"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Custom pipe can modify actual value of variable apart from different presention in HTML.",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "True"
            },
            {
                "B": "False"
            },
            {
                "C": null
            },
            {
                "D": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In Angular routing, below tag is used to render matched component via active route.",
        "answer": "C",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "<router></router>"
            },
            {
                "B": "<router-output></router-output>"
            },
            {
                "C": "<router-outlet></router-outlet>"
            },
            {
                "D": "<router-display></router-display>"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "We need to call below method of RouterModule for providing all routes in AppModule",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "RouterModule.forChild"
            },
            {
                "B": "RouterModule.forRoot"
            },
            {
                "C": "RouterModule"
            },
            {
                "D": "RouterModule.import"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Async Pipe subscribes to observer and update expression whenever there is data sent from observer",
        "answer": "A",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "True"
            },
            {
                "B": "False"
            },
            {
                "C": null
            },
            {
                "D": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Below command is used to run Static Code analysis of Angular application?",
        "answer": "1",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "ng build"
            },
            {
                "B": "ng profile"
            },
            {
                "C": "ng lint"
            },
            {
                "D": "ng serve"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Router service needs to be explicitly provided in angular module to use it in other component via DI",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "True"
            },
            {
                "B": "False"
            },
            {
                "C": null
            },
            {
                "D": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "We can chain multiple pipe in a single expression along with “async” pipe",
        "answer": "A",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "True"
            },
            {
                "B": "False"
            },
            {
                "C": null
            },
            {
                "D": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Below component represent “target/host” DOM element inside Directive’s constructor",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "Element"
            },
            {
                "B": "ElementRef"
            },
            {
                "C": "Host"
            },
            {
                "D": "Target"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "To build application in production mode, use below command",
        "answer": "C",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "ng build"
            },
            {
                "B": "ng serve"
            },
            {
                "C": "ng build --prod"
            },
            {
                "D": "ng lint"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Directive can listen to host/target events using below decoarator",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "@Listener"
            },
            {
                "B": "@HostListener"
            },
            {
                "C": "@OnListener"
            },
            {
                "D": "@TargetListener"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Using below wild card we can define page not found route",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "*"
            },
            {
                "B": "**"
            },
            {
                "C": "404"
            },
            {
                "D": "^"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "There can be more than one <router-outlet> element in angular application",
        "answer": "A",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "True"
            },
            {
                "B": "False"
            },
            {
                "C": null
            },
            {
                "D": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Below service can be used to extract route parameters inside component",
        "answer": "C",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "Router"
            },
            {
                "B": "Route"
            },
            {
                "C": "ActivatedRoute"
            },
            {
                "D": "CurrentRoute"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "HTTP service’s get/put/post/delete function returns",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "object of type “any”"
            },
            {
                "B": "Observable"
            },
            {
                "C": "Json data"
            },
            {
                "D": "callback function"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "In AOT compilation mode, browser gets angular compiler along with website content",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "True"
            },
            {
                "B": "False"
            },
            {
                "C": null
            },
            {
                "D": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Observer sends data to multiple clients via below method",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "send()"
            },
            {
                "B": "next()"
            },
            {
                "C": "emit()"
            },
            {
                "D": "publish()"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "By default, component’s change detection strategy is set to",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "OnPush"
            },
            {
                "B": "Default"
            },
            {
                "C": "Reactive"
            },
            {
                "D": "OnPull"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "One component can be declared inside more than one NgModule",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "True"
            },
            {
                "B": "False"
            },
            {
                "C": null
            },
            {
                "D": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "To use HttpClient component you need to import below module",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "HttpModule"
            },
            {
                "B": "HttpClientModule"
            },
            {
                "C": "Http"
            },
            {
                "D": "None of the above"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "Below pseudo class represent void => * animation state",
        "answer": "A",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": ":enter"
            },
            {
                "B": ":leave"
            },
            {
                "C": null
            },
            {
                "D": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "HTTP service is called event if observer doesn’t have “subscribe” method",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "True"
            },
            {
                "B": "false"
            },
            {
                "C": null
            },
            {
                "D": null
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "A component can have child route defined using below property",
        "answer": "B",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "routes"
            },
            {
                "B": "children"
            },
            {
                "C": "routeCollection"
            },
            {
                "D": "None of the above"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "question": "OnPush is faster in performance than Default change detection strategy",
        "answer": "A",
        "options": [
            {
                "A": "True"
            },
            {
                "B": "False"
            },
            {
                "C": null
            },
            {
                "D": null
            }
        ]
    }
]